<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science Portfolio on Fahad Mehfooz</title>
    <link>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science Portfolio on Fahad Mehfooz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 11:00:59 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Health Insurance Cross Sell Prediction</title>
      <link>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-17/</guid>
      <description>We have an insurance company as our client that has provided Health Insurance to its customers. Now they want a model to predict whether the policyholders from last year will be interested in Vehicle Insurance provided by the company. Such a model will be extremely helpful to the company because it can then accordingly plan its communication strategy to reach out to those customers and optimise its business model and revenue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EDA Worldbank EdStats</title>
      <link>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-16/</guid>
      <description>We are provided with a dataset named World Bank EdStats that contains 3665 indicators describing education access ( primary, secondary and tertiary), GDP, literacy rate, population growth and technical aptitude (PISA, TIMSS, PIRLS).
  The idea of the project is to analyze the data, mark the variation of indicators across the globe and group the countries according to their similarities and differences.
  After exploring the dataset, we tried to form a key approach to process the dataset to find the underlying patterns across all countries for all the indicators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pneumonia Classfication Using PyTorch</title>
      <link>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-15/</guid>
      <description>To Detect and Classify pneumonia using CNN. I have used pytorch for classification. Images have been transformed, reshaped, rotated and normalized. Prepared train and test data. Took batch size of 64. Classifying images to one of the 2 categories: Normal and pneumona. Data augmentation to include more images.  Source Code</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Recommendation System Using SVD</title>
      <link>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-14/</guid>
      <description>Joined the user rating and book dataframes. Created unique id for every ISBN, as later on when entering an on app it would be easier for the user. Built a pivot matrix of user ids and unique ids. Built a collaborative recommendation system. Used Decomposition vectors as 15, as more the factors higher information can be retained when combining the matrix. Wrote a function to find top cosine similarity and return the similar books.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sarcastic Or Not: Deployment With Bidirectiona/LSTM/CNN/LR </title>
      <link>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-13/</guid>
      <description>Classifying different comments to whether they are Sarcasic or not. Dataset has 1010773 rows. There was no imbalance in data. Took a test split of 20%. Converting the tokens using a TF-IDF vectorizer. Also, creating a word embedding for CNN/BiDirectional LSTM model. Performed EDA on the features. Models trained with BiDirectional, CNN, and Logistic Regression. Created an app on Flask and deployed it on Heroku.   Source Code</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Credit Analysis With Knn/Dtree/Rf/Bagging/ANN</title>
      <link>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-11/</guid>
      <description>The data is related with direct marketing campaigns of a Portuguese banking institution. The marketing campaigns were based on phone calls. Often, more than one contact to the same client was required, in order to access if the product (bank term deposit) would be (&amp;lsquo;yes&amp;rsquo;) or not (&amp;lsquo;no&amp;rsquo;) subscribed. Classifying if the term deposit would be subscribed or not. Dataset contains 41188 rows and 21 columns. Class imbalance observed for target variable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentiment Analysis Using: SVM/NaiveBayes/Bagging/Boosting/RandomForest-LSTM</title>
      <link>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-12/</guid>
      <description>Classifying different tweets of users into the categories : Positive and Negative. Took a test split of 20%. Converting the tokens using a TF-IDF vectorizer. Models trained with SVM, NaiveBayes, Bagging with MultinomialNb, AdaBoosting and RandomForest. Tuning the hyperprameters of all the models. Plotting precision-recall and roc-auc curves.   Source Code</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Stock Prediction With Stacked LSTM</title>
      <link>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-10/</guid>
      <description>We are provided with 6 variables describing the stock market trend for google. The task is to predict the future stock market price on the basis of past data. Here, I have taken past 100 days data to predict the next day&amp;rsquo;s stock price. I used an LSTM model because of it is powerful in storing sequence. After building the model, I used keras tuner to tune the hyperparameters of the model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brain Tumor Detection Using Keras And Pytorch</title>
      <link>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-9/</guid>
      <description>To Detect and Classify Brain Tumor using, CNN and TL; as an asset of Deep Learning and to examine the tumor position(segmentation). Prepared train and test data. Classifying brain images to one of the 4 categories: glioma_tumor, no_tumor, meningioma_tumor and pituitary_tumor. Data augmentation to include more images. Trained a CNN using keras and pytorch both. Used 4 convolutional layers, a dropout layer to avoid overfitting and compiled the model using Adam optimizer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classification On Prudential Life Insurance With Model Interpretation</title>
      <link>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-8/</guid>
      <description>We are provided with over a hundred variables describing attributes of life insurance applicants. The task is to predict the &amp;ldquo;Response&amp;rdquo; variable for each Id in the test set. &amp;ldquo;Response&amp;rdquo; is an ordinal measure of risk that has 8 levels. Handling null values and the class imbalance. Built tree based models,logistic regression and stacked models. Doing a feature importance check for all the models. Interpreting the model, how every feature is pushing towards which target response.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investigating The Myths Related To Vaccines (EDA).</title>
      <link>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-5-/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-5-/</guid>
      <description>Objective: Investigating the myths related to vaccines and to perform sentiment analysis. Dataset contains 1566 rows and 8 columns. Found out polarity and sensitivity of categorical columns. Built a corpus and removed the stopwords. Performed EDA. Built wordcloud for positive and negative words.   Source Code</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To Predict The Activity A Person Is Doing.</title>
      <link>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-4/</guid>
      <description>Objective: To predict the activity a person is doing. Label encoded the target variable. Used min max scaling to scale the data. The obtained dataset has been randomly partitioned into two sets, where 70% of the volunteers was selected for generating the training data and 30% the test data. Hypertuned the based model to find the number of layers, units and the activation functions needed.   Source Code</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diabetic Or Not?</title>
      <link>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>Objective: To predict whether or not a patient has diabetes, based on certain diagnostic measurements included in the dataset. Dealt with class imbalance using SMOTE. Divided the data into train and test data. Performed oversampling on train dataset/ Trained on multiple models like Logistic Regression, SVM, Bernoulli Naive Bayes, Gaussian Naive Bayes, KNN, and XGBoost.   Source Code</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EDA and Predictive Modelling On Rain In Australia With Model Deployment</title>
      <link>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>Dataset contains 145460 rows and 23 columns. Removing the outliers. Oversampling the train data to get more balanced data using SMOTE. Trained on multiple models like Logistic Regression, XGBoost, Bernoulli Naive Bayes, Gaussian Naive Bayes, and RandomForest. Built the app using Flask. Deployed the model on Heroku.   Try out the app
Source Code</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cat Image Classifier Using Transfer-Learning</title>
      <link>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>Classifying different images of cats into the following categories : Bombay, Calico, Burmese, Himalayan, Munchkin, Ragdoll, Siberian, British Shorthair, Russian Blue, and Dilute Calico. Trained the model on 11740 images. Dealt with class imbalance. Transfer learning is applied to train the model. Augmenting the data using an image data generator. Pretrained Model used: InceptionV3   Source Code</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medical Chatbot for Novel COVID-19.</title>
      <link>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/publications-blogs/publication-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/publications-blogs/publication-1/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: Conversational agents or more universally known as the chatbot were industrialized to respond to user’s queries in a particular domain. Chatbot would serve as a software delegate which enables a computer to converse with human via natural language. A chatbot is a human-like conversational character (Shaikh et al. Int J Eng Sci Comput 6:3117–3119, 2016 [1]. This technology was coined in 1960s, with the intention to impersonate a human (how he would reply to a particular situation) so that the user feels that he is talking to a real person and not a machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medical Chatbot for Novel COVID-19.</title>
      <link>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/publications/publication-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/publications/publication-1/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: Conversational agents or more universally known as the chatbot were industrialized to respond to user’s queries in a particular domain. Chatbot would serve as a software delegate which enables a computer to converse with human via natural language. A chatbot is a human-like conversational character (Shaikh et al. Int J Eng Sci Comput 6:3117–3119, 2016 [1]. This technology was coined in 1960s, with the intention to impersonate a human (how he would reply to a particular situation) so that the user feels that he is talking to a real person and not a machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Malaria Classification: CNN Vs ResNet50 Vs VGG19 Vs InceptionV3</title>
      <link>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-7/</guid>
      <description>Classifying different images of cells into the categories : Infected and Uninfected. Trained the model on 27,558 images. Took a test split of 20%. Models trained with CNN, ResNet50, VGG19 and InceptionV3. Preparing the image path and storing them in a dataframe along with their labels. Augmenting the data using an image data generator.   Source Code</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NLP Based Chatbot.</title>
      <link>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-6-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-6-/</guid>
      <description>Take an input from the user using speech on what you want to search. Download the data from newspaper on the disease matching user&amp;rsquo;s input. Tokenize, lemmatize and stemming the data. Vectorize the downloaded text and evaluate how important a word is to a document. Using cosine similarity , find how similar the downloaded text is to user&amp;rsquo;s search.  Source Code</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In what scenarios are machine learning models safe to apply?</title>
      <link>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/publications/publication-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/publications/publication-2/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: Confidence is necessary as it acts as the base when developing a machine learning model. But is it always reliable? While developing model, different aspects should be considered like security, data for training shouldn’t be flawed, risk management should be handled, etc. By this paper, I would address how someone can build a trustworthy model, what problems should be addressed and how to remove those issues.
Link to the research paper</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Me</title>
      <link>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/contact/</guid>
      <description>Find me on these social media platforms.
   Platform URL     GitHub: https://github.com/fahadmehfooz   Kaggle: https://www.kaggle.com/fahadmehfoooz   Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/fahad-m-469520188/   Email: fahad.mehfoooz@gmail.com    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
