<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science Portfolio on Fahad Mehfooz</title>
    <link>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science Portfolio on Fahad Mehfooz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 11:00:59 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Classification On Prudential Life Insurance With Model Interpretation</title>
      <link>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-8/</guid>
      <description>We are provided with over a hundred variables describing attributes of life insurance applicants. The task is to predict the &amp;ldquo;Response&amp;rdquo; variable for each Id in the test set. &amp;ldquo;Response&amp;rdquo; is an ordinal measure of risk that has 8 levels. Handling null values and the class imbalance. Built tree based models,logistic regression and stacked models. Doing a feature importance check for all the models. Interpreting the model, how every feature is pushing towards which target response.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investigating The Myths Related To Vaccines (EDA).</title>
      <link>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-5-/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-5-/</guid>
      <description>Objective: Investigating the myths related to vaccines and to perform sentiment analysis. Dataset contains 1566 rows and 8 columns. Found out polarity and sensitivity of categorical columns. Built a corpus and removed the stopwords. Performed EDA. Built wordcloud for positive and negative words.   Link to GitHub repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To Predict The Activity A Person Is Doing.</title>
      <link>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-4/</guid>
      <description>Objective: To predict the activity a person is doing. Label encoded the target variable. Used min max scaling to scale the data. The obtained dataset has been randomly partitioned into two sets, where 70% of the volunteers was selected for generating the training data and 30% the test data. Hypertuned the based model to find the number of layers, units and the activation functions needed.   Link to GitHub repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To Predict Whether Or Not A Patient Has Diabetes.</title>
      <link>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>Objective: To predict whether or not a patient has diabetes, based on certain diagnostic measurements included in the dataset. Dealt with class imbalance using SMOTE. Divided the data into train and test data. Performed oversampling on train dataset/ Trained on multiple models like Logistic Regression, SVM, Bernoulli Naive Bayes, Gaussian Naive Bayes, KNN, and XGBoost.   Link to GitHub repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EDA and Predictive Modelling On Rain In Australia</title>
      <link>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>Dataset contains 145460 rows and 23 columns. Removing the outliers. Oversampling the train data to get more balanced data using SMOTE. Trained on multiple models like Logistic Regression, XGBoost, Bernoulli Naive Bayes, Gaussian Naive Bayes, and RandomForest.   Link to GitHub repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cat Image Classifier Using Transfer-Learning</title>
      <link>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>Classifying different images of cats into the following categories : Bombay, Calico, Burmese, Himalayan, Munchkin, Ragdoll, Siberian, British Shorthair, Russian Blue, and Dilute Calico. Trained the model on 11740 images. Dealt with class imbalance. Transfer learning is applied to train the model. Augmenting the data using an image data generator. Pretrained Model used: InceptionV3   Link to GitHub repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medical Chatbot for Novel COVID-19.</title>
      <link>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/publications-blogs/publication-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/publications-blogs/publication-1/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: Conversational agents or more universally known as the chatbot were industrialized to respond to user’s queries in a particular domain. Chatbot would serve as a software delegate which enables a computer to converse with human via natural language. A chatbot is a human-like conversational character (Shaikh et al. Int J Eng Sci Comput 6:3117–3119, 2016 [1]. This technology was coined in 1960s, with the intention to impersonate a human (how he would reply to a particular situation) so that the user feels that he is talking to a real person and not a machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medical Chatbot for Novel COVID-19.</title>
      <link>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/publications/publication-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/publications/publication-1/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: Conversational agents or more universally known as the chatbot were industrialized to respond to user’s queries in a particular domain. Chatbot would serve as a software delegate which enables a computer to converse with human via natural language. A chatbot is a human-like conversational character (Shaikh et al. Int J Eng Sci Comput 6:3117–3119, 2016 [1]. This technology was coined in 1960s, with the intention to impersonate a human (how he would reply to a particular situation) so that the user feels that he is talking to a real person and not a machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Malaria Classification: CNN Vs ResNet50 Vs VGG19 Vs InceptionV3</title>
      <link>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-7/</guid>
      <description>Classifying different images of cells into the categories : Infected and Uninfected. Trained the model on 27,558 images. Took a test split of 20%. Models trained with CNN, ResNet50, VGG19 and InceptionV3. Preparing the image path and storing them in a dataframe along with their labels. Augmenting the data using an image data generator.   Link to GitHub repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NLP Based Chatbot.</title>
      <link>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-6-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/post/project-6-/</guid>
      <description>Take an input from the user using speech on what you want to search. Download the data from newspaper on the disease matching user&amp;rsquo;s input. Tokenize, lemmatize and stemming the data. Vectorize the downloaded text and evaluate how important a word is to a document. Using cosine similarity , find how similar the downloaded text is to user&amp;rsquo;s search.  Link to GitHub repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In what scenarios are machine learning models safe to apply?</title>
      <link>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/publications/publication-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/publications/publication-2/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: Confidence is necessary as it acts as the base when developing a machine learning model. But is it always reliable? While developing model, different aspects should be considered like security, data for training shouldn’t be flawed, risk management should be handled, etc. By this paper, I would address how someone can build a trustworthy model, what problems should be addressed and how to remove those issues.
Link to the research paper</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Me</title>
      <link>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahadmehfooz.github.io/Fahad_Portfolio/contact/</guid>
      <description>Find me on these social media platforms.
   Platform URL     GitHub: https://github.com/fahadmehfooz   Kaggle: https://www.kaggle.com/fahadmehfoooz   Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/fahad-m-469520188/   Email: fahad.mehfoooz@gmail.com    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
